# Jose R. Velazquez Gonzalez

🕈 Victoria, British Columbia 🗷 joserobertovg@gmail.com 🔲 (778) 700-6364 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/joservelazquez/

https://analystjose.com/

#### **SUMMARY**

Fast-learning data analyst with 12+ years experience in diverse businesses, developing unique insights from operations to management. Enthusiastic about processing, analyzing, and interpreting data to identify key metrics to drive growth, using tools such as R, SQL and Tableau. Strong business acumen and outstanding communications skills to create and present accurate reports and visualizations.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Online Sales Specialist**

Vetta

#### March 2020 - Present, Monterrey, Mexico

- Designed Tableau dashboards to perform a business analysis and present findings to stakeholders, focusing on Sales and AR.
- · Built e-commerce stores (Shopify and Mercado Libre) including layout, themes, descriptions, images, and prices for 200+ products.
- · Delivered prompt customer service on Messenger, WhatsApp, and e-mail; reducing response times to less than 1 hour.

# **Operations Auditor**

Coppel

#### January 2017 - August 2019, Zacatecas, Mexico

- · Analyzed individual store operations from the database to select unusual and/or suspicious operations to prevent fraud.
- · Performed retail stores, warehouses, and distribution centers audits, evaluating performance and generating auditing reports.
- · Reviewed processes, receipts, documents, and inventories to generate a proper risk assessment for managers to make better decisions.

**Insurance Agent** 

Seguros Monterrey New York Life

July 2015 - January 2017, San Luis Potosi, Mexico

- · Arranged meetings evaluate individual clients' needs and goals to create long-term savings, investing, and retirement plans.
- · Explained in detail each individual policy coverage as per the current law of insurances and sureties.
- · Certified insurance agent in Mexico by CNSF (National Insurance and Surety Commission).

## **Customer Service Specialist**

Telcel

## December 2013 - March 2015, San Luis Potosi, Mexico

- · Delivered outstanding face-to-face customer service, sales, quotation, billing, problem solving and client retention.
- · Managed confidential information of hundreds of customers, creating and updating information on ERP.

#### **Administrative Assistant**

**Atena Bienes Raices** 

August 2009 - August 2013, San Luis Potosi, Mexico

- $\cdot \ Processed \ documents, collected \ client \ information, and \ filled \ out \ loan \ approval \ forms \ with \ banks \ and \ government \ agencies.$
- · Created and updated an Excel database with hundreds of homes listings, for sales persons to easily access the properties features.

## **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: SQL, R, Python

Software and Technologies: Tableau, Tableau Prep, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, Excel, Office 365, Zoom

Other skills: Native Spanish

#### **EDUCATION**

## Certificate in Business Intelligence and Data Analytics

University of Victoria · Victoria, British Columbia · 2022

#### **Certificate in Business Administration**

University of Victoria · Victoria, British Columbia · 2022

## **Bachelor's in Business Administration**

Minor in Finance  $\cdot$  Universidad del Valle de Mexico  $\cdot$  Mexico  $\cdot$  2009